{
  "dbmcqs":[
      { "question":"In the __________ normal form, a composite attribute is converted to individual attributes.",
       "choices":["First", "Second","Third","Fourth"],
       "answer":"a"
      },
      
      { "question":"A table on the many side of a one to many or many to many relationship must:",
       "choices":["Be in Second Normal Form (2NF)","Be in Third Normal Form (3NF)","Have a single attribute key","Have a composite key"],
       "answer":"d"
      },
      
      { "question":"Tables in second normal form (2NF):",
       "choices":[
           "Eliminate all hidden dependencies",
           "Eliminate the possibility of a insertion anomalies",
           "Have a composite key",
           "Have all non key fields depend on the whole primary key"
       ],
       "answer":"a"
      },
      
      { "question":"Which-one ofthe following statements about normal forms is FALSE?",
       "choices":[
           "BCNF is stricter than 3NF",
           "Lossless, dependency -preserving decomposition into 3 NF is always possible",
           "Loss less, dependency â€“ preserving decomposition into BCNF is always possible",
           "Any relation with two attributes is BCNF"
        ],
       "answer":"c"
      },
      
      { "question":"Functional Dependencies are the types of constraints that are based on______",
       "choices":[
           "Key",
           "Key revisited",
           "Superset key",
           "None of the mentioned"
       ],
       "answer":"a"
      },
      
      { "question":"Which is a bottom-up approach to database design that design by examining the relationship between attributes:",
       "choices":[
           "Functional dependency",
           "Database modeling",
           "Normalization",
           "Decomposition"
       ],
       "answer":"c"
      },
      
      { "question":"Which forms simplifies and ensures that there are minimal data aggregates and repetitive groups:",
       "choices":[
           "1NF",
           "2NF",
           "3NF",
           "All of the mentioned"
       ],
       "answer":"c"
      },
      
      { "question":"Which forms has a relation that possesses data about an individual entity:",
       "choices":[
           "2NF",
           "3NF",
           "4NF",
           "5NF"
       ],
       "answer":"c"
      },
      
      { "question":"Which forms are based on the concept of functional dependency:",
       "choices":[
           "1NF",
           "2NF",
           "3NF",
           "4NF"
       ],
       "answer":"c"
      },
      
      { "question":"Empdt1(empcode, name, street, city, state, pincode)<br>For any pincode, there is only one city and state. Also, for given street, city and state, there is just one pincode. In normalization terms, empdt1 is a relation in",
       "choices":[
           "1NF only",
           "2NF and hence also in 1 NF",
           "3NF and hence also in 2NF and 1NF",
           "BCNF and hence also in 3NF, 2NF and 1NF"],
       "answer":"b"
      }
   ]
}

